Jim Pick

- 989 Beatty St. Apt. 1407 Vancouver, BC V6Z 3C2 Canada
- jim@jimpick.com
- 604 788-0122
- http://jimpick.com/

SUMMARY

A full-stack engineer, with over 30 years experience. Trained as an Electrical Engineer, I've done everything from hacking kernels and writing firmware, to wrangling devops, databases and APIs, to using the latest HTML5 technologies to build MVP-style apps for iOS and Android. Creating the billing and analytics infrastructure for SaaS-based businesses is one of my specialties.

SKILLS

- Node.js
- Distributed Systems
- Linux
- Scalability
- JavaScript
- Open Source
- Java
- Backbone.js
- C

- Software Development
- Databases
- Agile Methodologies
- Perl
- Cloud Computing
- User Experience
- AngularJS
- PhoneGap

EXPERIENCE

Backblend Systems Inc

01 / 2013 - Present

Co-founder

Co-founder and software development lead at Backblend Systems - we provide mobile and web interactive development, user experience consulting, Javascript from frontend to backend, API and database wrangling, plus various other services. http://backblend.com

jimpick.com

05 / 2011 - 01 / 2013

Node.js Developer

Built apps and websites for clients.

Joyent

03 / 2009 - 04 / 2011

Software Engineer

Developer on the Smart Platform (server-side JavaScript platform built with Perl and Python). Created a billing system in JavaScript for use in Joyent's first self-service provisioning portal. Early user of Node.js (worked with Ryan Dahl). Prepared builds of Joyent SmartDatacenter and SmartOS.

jimpick.com

07 / 2008 - 03 / 2009

Freelance Developer

Built apps and websites for clients.

Bycast Inc.

07 / 2006 - 07 / 2008

Senior Software Architect

Developer on core provisioning software and member of build team.

Digeo 2002 - 2006

Senior Software Engineer

Member of build team. Maintained C/C++ compilers and toolchain and full Linux distribution cross-compiled to x86 and MIPS with hundreds of RPM packages. Built shared compile cluster farm using distcc.

Transvirtual Technologies

2000 - 2002

Senior Software Engineer

Linux kernel drivers for handheld devices. Porting of Linux distribution to new embedded devices. Profiling on clean room open source Java virtual machine implementation.

EDUCATION University of Victoria

1988 - 1993

Engineering, Electrical

LANGUAGES • Japanese